MICHELLE SEMAN

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Recent graduate with a passion for researching, art, and history. Over 10 years of museum experience, as well as studying research-based programs, has provided me with skills in research, but also with time management and delegation, communication skills, and creative thinking when obstacles arise.

EXPERIENCE

ARCHIVIST & LIBRARIAN / CURRENT /

Northwestern Michigan College

- Supplemental reference librarian
- College archivist

LOCAL HISTORY INTERN / June-July 2021 /

Traverse Area District Library

- Will be completing 40 hours in the local history department

SUBSTITUTE LIBRARIAN / 2020 - PRESENT /

Traverse Area District Library

- Training in all departments

ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT / 2020 - 2021 /

Designsmiths Architects

- Office and Records management duties

SALES ASSOCIATE / 2015 - 2020 /

Wood + Cloth

- Assisted customers with home goods purchases

ARCHIVAL INTERN / 2019 / 60 hours /

Grand Rapids City Archives and Records

- Processed and appraised backlog
- Cataloged

ASSISTANT REGISTRAR, INTERN/VOLUNTEER / 2007-2015 /

Dennos Museum Center

- Updated, cataloged, and archived museum collection
- Maintained museum collection records on Past Perfect
- Assisted in appraisals, exhibit preparation, and installation
- Digitized the Inuit Art print collection for digital and online access.

STUDENT LIFE

- Secretary Art History Association / University of Oregon
- Board Member Student Art Show / University of Oregon

CONTACT

+1 231 499 5650 semanmichelle@gmail.com 7858 Peaceful Valley Rd, Wiiliamsburg, MI 49690

EDUCATION

Certificate in Coding / Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Remote

Full Stack Development, 06/2022

Master's of Science / University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Milwaukee, WI

Library and Information

Sciences, 05/2020

- 3.9 GPA
- Concentration in Archives

Bachelor's of Art / University of Oregon Eugene, OR Art History, 06/2014

SKILLS

- . ArchivesSpace
- Collection Digitization
- Past Perfect Software
- Collective Access
- Adobe Photoshop, Acrobat
- . Evergreen OPAC
- MelCat
- . Adaptive

INTERESTS

Art History

Historical Fiction

Architecture

Hiking

Biking